Guide to the Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by William Styron, 1831-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (1998-0553)
  - Books and Periodicals Containing Materials about Styron (Box 8)
    - A Likely Story: One Summer with Lillian Hellman, (proof), by Rosemary Mahoney, 1998 (Box 9)
    - Conversations with Arthur Miller, edited by Matthew C. Roudane, 1987 (Box 9)
    - New York Days, by Willie Morris, 1993 (Box 9)
    - Continual Pilgrimage: American Writers in Paris, 1944-1960,by Christopher Sawyer-Laucanno, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Arthur Miller and Company, edited by Christopher Bigsby, 1990 (Box 9)
    - The American Literary Anthology, edited by William Styron, 1968 (Box 9)
    - The Writer's World, edited by Elizabeth Janeway, 1969 (Box 9)
    - A Writer's Capital, by Louis Auchincloss, 1974 (Box 9)
    - William Styron, by Richard Pearce, 1971(2 copies) (Box 9)
    - The Writers Desk, by Jill Krementz, 1996 (Box 9)
    - Writers Workshop: Study Guide, edited by Beth Littlejohn, 1982 (Box 9)
    - The Old Gringo, by Carlos Fuentes, 1989 (Box 9)
      Dedicated to Styron.
    - The NPR Interviews, 1995, edited by Robert Siegel, 1995 (Box 9)
      Interview with Styron.
    - Ploughshares, Vol.1, No.3, 1972 (Box 9)
    - How They Met, edited by Nancy Cobb, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Savage Grace,(uncorrected proof) by Natalie Robins and Steven M. L. Aronson, 1985 (Box 9)
    - The Poet at the Piano, by Michiko Kakutani, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Terrains of the Heart, by Willie Morris, 1981 (Box 9)
    - Writers, photographs by Sally Soames, 1995 (Box 9)
    - The Root of All Evil, by John Kenny Crane, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Words and Faces, by Hiram Haydn, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Clippings and Periodicals Containing Materials by Styron (Box 10)
    Chiefly published excerpts of novels, arranged by novel in chronological order, and short non-fiction pieces by and about Styron. See also Box 13 (oversize).
    - Set This House on Fire (Box 10)
      - The Paris Review, 22, Autumn-Winter, 1959-60 (Box 10)
    - The Confession of Nat Turner (Box 10)
      - The Nation, 1967, Oct. 16 (Box 10)
      - Harper's Magazine, 1967, Sept. (Box 10)
      - Time, 1967, Oct. 13 (Box 10)
      - The Hollins Critique, 1967, Dec. (Box 10)
      - "Reflections on Nat Turner," James T. Cleland, 1968 (Box 10)
    - The Long March (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, (1 folder) (Box 10)
    - Sophie's Choice (Box 10)
      - Esquire, 1976, Sept. (Box 10)
      - Esquire, 1976, Apr. (Box 10)
      - Newsweek, 1979, May 20 (Box 10)
      - Moviegoer, 1983 Jan. (Box 10)
    - Darkness Visible (Box 10)
      - Vanity Fair, 1989, Dec. (Box 10)
      - Duke Magazine, 1990-1991,Dec.-Jan. (Box 10)
    - Tidewater Morning (Box 10)
      - Esquire, 1987, Aug. (Box 10)
      - Lord John Press Catalog, 1992 (Box 10)
      - Dear Reader, Square Books, 1993, Sept.-Oct. (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous Writings by Styron (Box 10)
      - The New Republic, 1959, Apr.6 (Box 10)
      - Harper's Magazine, 1968, Apr. (Box 10)
      - Esquire, 1983, Dec. (Box 10)
      - Duke: To Cross a Threshold, 1984 (Box 10)
      - The Archive, 1987,Spring (Box 10)
      - Esquire, 1989, Apr. (Box 10)
      - The Nation, 1993, Jan. 4-11 (Box 10)
      - At Random, 1993,Fall (Box 11)
      - At Random, 1997,Spring (Box 11)
      - The New Yorker, 1998, Aug. 17 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Writings about Styron (Box 11)
      - New York, 1980, Oct. 20 (Box 11)
      - Duke Magazine, 1984, July-Aug. (Box 11)
      - Duke Magazine, 1984, Sept.-Oct. (Box 11)
      - Esquire, 1986, Dec. (Box 11)
      - The Davidsonian, 1986, Apr. 25 (Box 11)
      - Duke Magazine, 1990, Apr.-May (Box 11)
      - Duke Magazine, 1992, Mar.-Apr. (Box 11)
      - Glimmer Train, 1993,Winter (Box 11)
      - Dear Reader, Square Books, 1993, Mar.-Apr. (Box 11)
      - "Oxford Conference for the Book," 1993 (Box 11)
      - Southern Register, 1993,Spring (Box 11)
      - Davidson Journal, 1994,Summer (Box 11)
      - Duke Magazine, 1995, Jan.-Feb. (Box 11)
      - Firsts, 1995, Feb. (Box 11)
      - Davidson Journal, 1996, Winter (Box 11)
      - "A Conversation with William Styron," and "A Conversation with James West," 1997 (Box 11)
        Printed from the internet in 1997.
      - Duke Magazine, 1997, July-Aug. (Box 11)
      - Southern Register, 1997,Summer (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript Pages, Correspondence, and Ephemera (Box 11)
    - Two typed excerpts from The Confessions of Nat Turner, signed by Styron, undated (Box 11)
    - Typed excerpt from Lie Down in Darkness, signed by Styron, undated (Box 11)
    - Typed excerpt from This Quiet Dust, signed by Styron, undated (Box 11)
    - Photograph of Styron, by Nancy Crampton; signed by Styron. (Box 11)
    - Correspondence with Vearl Moody, (3 letters) (Box 11)
      One autographed postcard, 1979, May 30;Two autographed letters, 1982, Nov. 3and undated
    - Correspondence with Stuart Wright, 1977-1984, (39 letters) (Box 11)
      Chiefly letters from Styron to Wright. Wright owned Palaemon Press in Winston-Salem, N.C. and published many limited editions of Styron's work. In some correspondence, Styron addresses Wright as Lt. Col. Stuart Wright and signs himself as Maj. Gen. William Styron, CSA.
    - Miscellaneous Promotional Materials, (1 folder) (Box 11)
  - Audio and Video Recordings (Box 12)
    - William Styron reading from 'Lie Down in Darkness,' Caliope, 1963 (Box 12)
      33 1/3 rpm long playing 7" vinyl record.
    - William Styron Reads His Works, Jeffrey Norton Audio Forum, 1968 (Box 12)
      Styron reads from Nat Turner and The Long March.
    - Writers Workshop, Center for the Study of Southern Culture, 1981 (Box 12)
      VHS recording of Styron speaking to James Dickey's class.
    - William Styron reading from Sophie's Choice, 1986 (Box 12)
      Audio cassette of Styron reading at Davidson College.
    - Darkness Visible: A Memoir of Madness, Random House Sound Editions, 1990 (Box 12)
      2 audio cassettes, read by Styron.
    - Conversation of William Styron, undated (Box 12)
      Home-recorded Beta cassette of a public television broadcast.
    - Lincoln Center Chamber Music, undated (Box 12)
      Home-recorded Beta cassette of a public television broadcast. Styron and Arthur Miller discuss music in their lives and work.
    - William Styron, An American Masterpiece, 1997 (Box 12)
      Home-recorded cassette of a 1-hour documentary. 2 copies - one Beta, one VHS.
    - "Sophie's Choice," directed by Alan J. Pakula, 1982 (Box 12)
      Home-recorded Beta video cassette.
    - Sophie's Choice, read by Norman Snow, Random House Audiobooks, 1986 (Box 12)
      2 sets of 2 cassettes each.
    - Naked in New York, 1994 (Box 12)
      Styron has a cameo appearance.
  - Clippings and Periodicals (Box 13)
    Clippings and oversize periodicals, 1951-1998,and undatedChiefly reviews and profiles of Styron. Includes some short non-fiction pieces by Styron. Listed chronologically.
    - "William Styron," New York Herald Tribune, 1951, Sept.9 (Box 13)
    - "A Rich, Moving Novel Introduces a Young Writer of Great Talent," by Howard Mumford Jones, New York Herald Tribune, 1951, Sept.9 (Box 13)
    - "Talk With William Styron," by David Dempsey, New York Times Book Review, 1951, Sept.9 (Box 13)
    - "In a Place Where Live is a Stranger" by John W. Aldridge, New York Times, 1951, Sept.9 (Box 13)
    - "Prose of Promise," by Harrison Smith, Saturday Review, 1952,Feb 16 (Box 13)
    - "Mrs. Aadland's little girl, Beverly," by William Styron, Esquire, 1961, Nov. (Box 13)
    - "Editorial: Faulkner's Legacy: 'Honor, Pity, Pride,'" Life Magazine, 1962, July 20 (Box 13)
    - "Catch $95," Newsweek, 1964, March9. (Box 13)
    - "Slave's Own Story of Virginia Revolt," by T.R. Gray, The Washington Post, 1967, Oct. 15 (Box 13)
    - "The Slave Who Became a Man," by Wilfred Sheed, New York Times Book Review, 1967, Oct.8 (Box 13)
    - "What People are Reading," Book World, 1967, Oct. 29 (Box 13)
    - "Nat Turner's Confession," by T.R. Gray, New York Post, 1967, Oct. 28 (Box 13)
    - "The Literary Attacks on Styron's Nat Turner," The [Washington] Sunday Star, 1968, Sept.1 (Box 13)
    - "In the Jungle," by William Styron, The New York Review of Books, 1968, Sept. 26 (Box 13)
    - "William Styron: Portrait of a Man Reading," interviewed by Charles Monaghan, The Washington Post Book World, 1968, Oct. 27 (Box 13)
    - " Truman Capote lists the books he will give his friends for Christmas," The Washington Post Book World, 1968, Dec.1 (Box 13)
    - "Italian Poets Gets $10,000 prize; Styron is Cited for Nat Turner," The New York Times, 1970, Mar. 10 (Box 13)
    - "Introduction," by William Styron, Taproot, 1978-1979,Winter (Box 13)
    - "Sophie's Choice: A Novel of Evil," by John Gardner, New York Times Book Review, 1979, May 27 (Box 13)
    - "Bestsellers" New York Times Book Review, 1979, July 22 (Box 13)
    - "Moujik 'n' Pulp Sandwich," by Lec Navarozov, Chronicles of Culture, 1979, Nov.-Dec. (Box 13)
    - "Updike, Styron, and Chrichton Celebrate Martha's Vineyard," The New York Times Magazine, 1980, June 15 (Box 13)
    - "Works in Progress," New York Times Book Review, 1982, June6 (Box 13)
    - "Interview with William Styron," by Michiko Kakutani, The New York Times Book Review, 1982, Dec. 12 (Box 13)
    - "Newsmakers," Newsweek, 1983, Feb. 18 (Box 13)
    - New York Times Books Review, 1983, Nov. 27 (Box 13)
    - The Duke Annual Fund Report, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
    - "Historians take another look at the confessions of Nat Turner," by Debbie Selinsky, The Duke Dialog, 1987, May 29 (Box 13)
    - "In the Hours Before Hiroshima," by William Styron, The Archive, 1987,Spring (Box 13)
    - "Nat Turner Revisited," by Dixie B. O'Conner, Leader Magazine, 1987, June4 (Box 13)
    - "Arts and letters academy picks 3," The [Memphis] Commercial Appeal, 1987, Dec.7 (Box 13)
    - "Duke Prof 'Imposes Order' On Work of William Styron," by Betty Hodges, The Durham Morning Herald, 1988, Jan. 17 (Box 13)
    - "World Statement in Support of Salman Rushdie," New York Review of Books, 1989, April 13 (Box 13)
    - "How the death of Faulkner came to Life," by William Thomas, The [Memphis] Commercial Appeal, 1989, Aug.5 (Box 13)
    - "Styron gift will launch NCSU fund," 1989 (Box 13)
    - "Darkness Visible: 'A Howling Tempest in the Brain'" by Victoria Glendinning, The New York Times Book Review, 1990, Aug. 19 (Box 13)
    - "On William Blackburn and Creative Imagination," by William Styron, The Duke Dialog, 1991, Sept. 13 (Box 13)
    - "Styron Speaks at Founders' Day," The Duke Insider, 1991, Nov. (Box 13)
    - "Novelist comes home to Duke," by David Folkenflik, The Durham Herald-Sun, 1991, Dec.6 (Box 13)
    - "Solid short stories probe a family," by Frederic Koeppel, The [Memphis] Commercial Appeal, 1993, Dec. 12 (Box 13)
    - "Historical Fiction and the Facts," Wilson Quarterly, 1993, Winter (2 copies) (Box 13)
    - "Disney can only mock slavery's pain," by William Styron, The [Memphis] Commercial Appeal, 1994 Aug.7 (Box 13)
    - "Exploring the Links Between Depression, Writers and Suicide," by William Grimes, New York Times, 1994, Nov. 14 (Box 13)
    - "A Wounded Healer: Review of Touched With Fire," by Marie Arana-Ward, Book World, 1996, Aug. 18 (Box 13)
    - "Pulitzer-winning author donates manuscript, other items to Duke," The Durham Herald-Sun, 1997, May 29 (Box 13)
    - "Library acquires Styron papers," by Noah Bartolucci, The Duke Dialog, 1997, June7 (Box 13)
    - "Styron, Biographer Swap Tales," The Raleigh News and Observer, 1998, Mar. 29 (Box 13)
    - "Review: William Styron: A Life," by Victor Strandberg, The Raleigh News and Observer, 1998, Mar. 29 (Box 13)
    - "The Confession of William Styron," by Jason Wagner, The Chronicle, 1998, Mar. 30 (Box 13)
    - "Review: William Styron: A Life," by Michale Pearson, The Washington Post Book World, 1998, May3 (Box 13)
    - "Film Review: 'Shadrach,'" The Wall Street Journal, 1998, Sept. 25 (Box 13)
    - The Faulkner Newsletter, 1998, Oct.-Dec. (Box 13)
    - "Stars Shine in 100th Archive," by Jon Hilsenrath, The Duke Chronicle, undated (Box 13)
    - "No, No!! Not A Kudo!!!" by Russell Baker, undated (Box 13)
    - "Legal Scholar, Writer Urge Rejection of Bork," undated (Box 13)
    - "Novelist Styron Addresses Graduates of Duke," undated (Box 13)
  - Confessions of Nat Turner (Box 14)
    - Confessions of Nat Turner, 1967 (Box 14)
      Carbon copy, with holograph corrections, of Styron's original typescript.
  - Limited Editions (Box 15)
    - The Four Seasons: Essay by William Styron, by Harold Altman, Pennsylvania State University Press, 1965 (Box 15)
  - Ephemera (Box 15)
    - Photograph of William Styron and James Jones. (Box 15)
    - Large gray Hanes cotton T-shirt. Back reads, "'I still maintain that the times get precisely the literature that they deserve.' William Styron. Paris Review, 1953," 1993 (Box 15)
    - The Vanishing South: the Art of Hubert Shuptrine, 1993Calendar with commentary by William Styron. (Box 15)
  - Manuscripts (Box 15)
    - Holograph manuscript page of an unidentified text, signed by Styron, undated (Box 15)
    - "Southern Fried Chicken," by William Styron, 1961 (Box 15)
- Accession 2001-0056 (Box 15)
  - Lie Down in Darkness, Bobbs-Merrill, 1951 (Box 1)
    Third printing, with long inscription by Styron to reviewer Maxwell Giesmar; includes Geismar's holograph comments and marks of emphasis.
  - The Confessions of Nat Turner, Random House, 1967 (Box 1)
    First edition; Herbert Aptheker's copy, signed by him and including his marks and annotations throughout.
  - Conversations with Willie Morris, University Press of Mississippi, 2000 (Box 1)
    First edition; contains many mentions of Styron.
  - Remembering Willie, University Press of Mississippi, 2000 (Box 1)
    First edition; includes Styron's It Cannot Be Long.
  - Dog Eat Dog, by Edward Bunker, St. Martin's Press, 1996 (Box 1)
    First edition; introduction by Styron.
  - All the Finest Girls, by Alexandra Styron, Little, Brown, 2001 (Box 1)
    First edition; signed by the author.
  - All the Finest Girls, by Alexandra Styron, Little, Brown, 2001 (Box 1)
    Uncorrected proof in original green wrappers.
  - But Now I See: The White Southern Racial Conversion Narrative, by Fred Hobson, Louisiana State University Press, 1999 (Box 1)
    Includes several mentions of Styron.
  - Onward!: 25 Years of Advice, Exhortation, and Inspiration from America's Best Commencement Speeches, Scribner, 2000 (Box 1)
    Includes excerpt from Styron's 1981 commencement speech at Duke.
  - Indian Country, by Philip Caputo, Bantam, 1987 (Box 1)
    Styron's advance reading copy of the first edition.
  - Three Minutes or Less: Life Lessons from America's Greatest Writers, Bloomsbury, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Unholy Ghost: Writers on Depression, Morrow, 2001 (Box 1)
    First edition; includes excerpt from Styron's Darkness Visible.
  - Dead Run: The Untold Story of Dennis Stockton and America's Only Mass Escape from Death Row, Times Books, 1999 (Box 1)
  - A Portrait of Southern Writers: Photographs by Curt Richter, Hill Street Press, 2000 (Box 2)
    First edition, signed by the photographer; includes portrait of Styron.
  - A Word to the Unwise, Wall Street Journal, May 26, 2000 (Box 2)
    Review by Dave Shiflett of Onward! book.
  - Printed material concerning Edward Bunker (Box 2)
  - Printed material including articles by or about Styron (Box 2)
    - American Heritage, October 1992 special issue (Box 2)
    - The New Yorker, December 13, 1999 issue (Box 2)
    - Oxford American, September/October 1999 issue (Box 2)
    - Southern Review of Literature, September 15, 1951 issue (Box 2)
    - Playboy, Vol. 15, No.12, December 1968 (Box 2)
  - An Evening with William Styron, program from gala tribute to Styron held at the Library of Virginia, December 2, 2000 (Box 2)
    Accompanied by articles printed from the internet about the event.
  - Admiral Robert Penn Warren and the Snows of Winter, A Tribute, by William Styron, Palaemon Press, 1978? (Box 2)
    Uncorrected proof.
  - Original manuscript review of Sophie's Choice, by Julian Symons (Box 2)
    Published as The Penalties of Survival in the [London] Times Literary Supplement, November 30, 1979.
  - Original camera-ready publisher's advertisement for The Confessions of Nat Turner (Box 2)
  - Original holograph manuscript of Styron's 1977 review of A Rumor of War by Philip Caputo (Box 2)
    First published in The New York Review of Books, 23 June 1977.
- Accession 2008-0081, (1 folder) (Box 2)
  One black-and-white signed photograph, and four pages of Styron's writing (two sheets are signed).
- Accession 2008-0325, (1 box and 1 folder) (Box 2)
  Two items of correspondence in one folder. Also includes a photograph and an undated screenplay, SET THIS HOUSE ON FIRE (in one box).